# **CHRISTOPHE FOYER**

christophe@cfoyer.com • www.cfoyer.com • (+1) 816-419-6150 US and French citizenships | Eligible to work without restriction in the USA and EEA

### **SUMMARY:**

Mechanical Engineer with experience in projects in mechatronics, software, aerospace and energy engineering. Demonstrated track record of finding creative solutions to engineering challenges while operating under tight budgets.

- CAD, FEA and CFD
- Prototyping and Fabrication (metals, plastics, and composites)
- Engineering Hand Calculations
- Embedded Systems and Software Development

## **EDUCATION:**

## **Washington University in Saint Louis**

Saint Louis, USA Aug 2014 – Dec 2017

Bachelor of Science in Mechanical Engineering; Minor in Energy Engineering

- RWTH Aachen, Germany (Summer 2017) – Energy & Mechatronics - School for International Training, Iceland (Summer 2015) – Energy

## **EXPERIENCE:**

## **Temporary Works Design (TWD)**

London, United Kingdom Nov 2018 – Present

Design Engineer

TWD is an engineering company specialized in creating custom-designed tools and structures to perform transport and installation projects.

- Design of bespoke equipment and structures for civil engineering contractors using Autodesk Inventor
- Verification of structural parameters using engineering hand calculations and finite element analysis

Tata Steel Europe

Ijmuiden, Netherlands

Mechanical Engineering Intern – Student SWAT Team

Apr 2018 – July 2018

Tata Steel is Europe's second largest steel producer, with steelmaking in the UK and Netherlands, and manufacturing plants across Europe.

- Successfully built a large-scale thermal simulation in Python reducing temperature estimation error by 82.4%
- Proof-of-concept enabling potential savings on the order of one million euros per year if implemented
- Organized a training session on collaborative code management (git) for the department

## Wash. U. Design/Build/Fly Competition Team Founder

Washington University in St. Louis, USA

Mar 2016 – Dec 2017

WUDBF is an aerospace-oriented engineering team that attends yearly competitions that are sponsored by the American Institute of Aeronautics and Astronautics (AIAA).

- Co-led the team to 12<sup>th</sup> place out of 138 teams at the AIAA DBF 2017 competition
- Led the systems team to design and optimize aircraft internal systems through MATLAB simulations
- Managed an operating budget of \$10,000 to purchase components and organize travel to competition
- Scheduled weekly meetings with the team and coordinated project deadlines

## **PROJECTS:**

[resume.cfoyer.com/#projects]

### Senior Design Project – Low-Cost Concentrator Photovoltaics

Aug 2017 – Dec 2017

Foyer, Christophe; Rangwala, Adam; and Nana, Deep, "Water Lenses for Low-Cost Concentrator Photovoltaics" (2017). Mechanical Engineering Design Project Class. (https://openscholarship.wustl.edu/mems411/71/)

Coding of FEA and ray tracing software for optics simulation in MATLAB for the development of a sunlight tracking circuit using Arduino. Proof of concept prototype increasing solar cell output by 860%.

#### **SKILLS:**

CAD / FEA / CFD | SolidWorks, Autodesk Inventor, XFLR5

Programming Python, MATLAB, Simulink, HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Fabrication Machining (Lathe, Mill), Composite wet layup (FG/CF), 3D-Printing, GD&T

Software / OS Microsoft Office Suite, LaTeX, Windows, Linux

Languages Bilingual English – French • Basic German and Icelandic

<sup>\*</sup>References available upon request